MICHIEL KLEINNIJENHUIS

Utrecht (NL) | michiel.kl@gmail.com | LinkedIn

ABOUT

Data scientist with a background in 3D image analysis. I have ample experience in developing methods to translate raw data into clear answers by combining components and integrating deep learning techniques. Python coding, creative analyses, visualising big data are strong points. I love putting my skills to use in solving societal issues.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Python, C/C++, Git, Matlab, Unix scripting, HPC big data, machine learning, data stewardship, modelling, visualisation commitment, flexibility, problem-solving, collaboration Dutch, English, German (basic), Spanish (basic)

EXPERIENCE

2019 – 2022 Princess Maximá Center for pediatric oncology

Utrecht (NL)

Computational scientist

- Developing 3D microscopy analysis methods.
 Keywords: <u>deep learning</u>, <u>big data</u>, <u>distributed computing</u>
- Leading the small group of bioinfomaticians of the microscopy group.

2013 – 2018 University of Oxford

Oxford (UK)

Postdoctoral researcher

- Researching brain plasticity using MRI and electron microscopy.
 - Keywords: <u>python</u>, <u>HPC</u>, <u>MCMC modelling</u>
- Teaching FMRIB graduate course on MRI physics and analysis techniques.

2009 – 2013 **Donders institute**

Niimegen (NL)

PhD candidate

- Creating approaches in anatomical brain imaging for mapping structural brain networks.
 Keywords: diffusion MRI, tractography, white matter dissection
- Giving classes and practicals in brain anatomy (including course development).

2008 – 2009 NXP Semiconductors

Nijmegen (NL)

Reliability engineer

- Finding the root cause of an issue arising upon changing production plant of integrated circuits.
 Keywords: passivation cracks, pattern shift, temperature cycling
- Coordinating the various divisions involved in the research.

2006 – 2007 **Brainquiry R & D**

Nijmegen (NL)

Researcher in applied psychophysiology

- Developing methods for physiological measurements in the context of sports and neurofeedback.
 Keywords: <u>portable EEG</u>, <u>wearables</u>, <u>LabView</u>
- Coding software for neurofeedbacktherapy.

EDUCATION

2014 PhD Donders Graduate School for Cognitive Neuroscience

Radboud University Nijmegen

Nijmegen (NL)

- Thesis: "Imaging fibers in the brain"
- Advisors: Prof Dirk J. Ruiter and Prof David G. Norris

2007 MSc Cognitive Neuroscience

Radboud University Nijmegen

Nijmegen (NL)

- Thesis: "The development of a multipurpose biofeedback system."
- Adivors: Prof Jacques Duysens and Prof Stan (C.C.A.M) Gielen

2003 **BSc Technische Natuurkunde**

Saxion Hogeschool Enschede

Enschede (NL)

• Thesis: "Hoge Definitie Encefalografie: de gevolgen van samplefrequentieverlaging"

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Links to full lists and full texts: <u>papers</u> – <u>proceedings</u> – <u>chapters</u> – <u>patents</u> – <u>theses</u>

van Ineveld, R. L.*, <u>Kleinnijenhuis, M.</u>*, ..., Wehrens, E. J., & Rios, A. C. (2021).

Revealing the spatio-phenotypic patterning of cells in healthy and tumor tissues with mLSR-3D and STAPL-3D. *Nature Biotechnology*, 39(10), 1239–1245.

https://doi.org/10.1038/s41587-021-00926-3 *co-first authors

Kleinnijenhuis, M., Zerbi, V., ..., Barth, M., & van Cappellen van Walsum, A.-M. (2013). Layer-specific diffusion weighted imaging in human primary visual cortex in vitro. *Cortex*, 49(9), 2569–2582.

https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2012.11.015

INTERESTS

Running – Bootcamp – Travel – Photography – Food – Tech – Literature